When a girl has a heart of stone, there's only one way to melt it. Just add Ice.
Cool as Ice is a romance, music, comedy film directed by David Kellogg.
Freewheeling, motorcycle-riding musician Johnny rolls into a small town with
his band, and meets Kathy, an honor student who catches his eye.
Meanwhile, Kathy's father, after being in the Witness Protection Program, is finally tracked down
by two corrupt cops he escaped from years ago, who want the money he owes them.
Johnny, played by Vanilla Ice.
Kathy, played by Kristin Minter.
Singer at First Club, played by Naomi Campbell.
Jazz, played by Deezer D.
Sir D., played by Kevin Hicks.
Princess, played by Allison Dean.
Cool as Ice is a 1991 American musical teen drama film, directed by David Kellogg, written
by David Stenn and starring rapper Vanilla Ice in his feature film debut.
The plot focuses on Johnny Van Owen, a freewheeling, motorcycle-riding rapper who arrives
in a small town and meets Kathy, an honor student who catches his eye.
Meanwhile, Kathy's father, who is in witness protection, is found by
the corrupt police officers he escaped from years ago.
Developed as a vehicle for Vanilla Ice, the film was widely panned by critics, and was a
box office bomb, grossing only $1.2 million from a $6 million budget.
The film explores themes of rap music, rapper,
witness protection, police corruption.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.